一部 報道された お台場が 水没したというニュースは
This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
誤報であることが 確認され
Earlier, it was reported that Odaiba has been flooded.
その他 世界各都市が太陽嵐によって
甚大な被害が出ているという情報も
That has since been revealed as a false alarm.
The reports that cities across the world have taken severe damage from solar storms were as well.
ネットワーク上に流れた誤った情報である 可能性も高く
一部では そもそも 太陽嵐は到達していないという情報もあり
This is likely to be erroneous information coming in over the network.
政府は 確認を急ぐとしています
There are even doubts of there being a solar flare to begin with.
そろそろ 気付くころか
Hopefully the government will soon step in to clear up the miscommunication.
ここを放棄して
They'll pick up on it soon enough.
射場に 戦力を集結する
All personnel to the launch pad.
ロケットの発射を 急がせろ
Hurry with the rocket launch preparations.
残酷なる時は いつか
In the end, time unforgiving
契約の地さえ引き裂くの
たくさんが生み出す恐怖
Will draw the blood of covenant
真理のために今ここにいるよ
Everything scatters, leaving void
意外なCrazy
But we're here for the greater good
We Meet
目眩くこのシーン うかつな選択
Crazier than everyone, we need to dazzle
浮かび行く景色はやがて鮮やかに
The stage with our careless justice
And the scenery floating by becomes clearer
時間をすり抜ける
咆筺のメシア
As the Messiah of the Shoutbox slips through time
笑って 泣いて
僕らの一つの夢
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
願って 叫んで
どこまでも遠くへ
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
走って 飛ばして
気持ちの集まる場所
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
Run and break that place where feelings gather
愛しすぎるこの空の下で
Under this sky, oh so dear
明日を証明したくて
We're fighting for the future
本字幕由諸神字幕組出品,僅供學習交流之用 更多中日雙語字幕，請登錄 www.kamigami.org        ---諸神字幕組---          台本：卷                 翻译:臭屁匠 苜汐瞳            校对: mam　          后期:Ressul
Good! Remove the plating.
いいから 外せって言ってんだろ
B-But... this...
で… でも これじゃあ…
We're trying to reduce the weight as much as we can to increase the speed.
なるべく 軽量化を図ってスピードを上げるんです
ボクシングでいえば ウエート 落として
Gunvarrel! Launch!
It's like boxing! Dodge, dodge, and counter!
かわして かわして カウンター 狙いってこった
Got it?
分かったか
Sit down.
座れ
Father...
父さん
本当に 大丈夫なの？
Is this really okay?
It looks like their forces are concentrated around JAXA.
武装集団はＪＡＸＡに 戦力を 集中したみたいだって言ってたし
We'll have to be careful.
まあ 注意は必要ですけどね
A-A-Airi too?
あ… あ… 愛理たんも？
うん どうしてもって…
She insisted.
I feel like... there's something I have to do.
何か… 思い出せそうな気がするんです
What's that?
何を？
Well... what could it be?
さあ… 何でしょう？
This must be the EGI system.
これが ＥＧＩシステムですか
Yeah, it should have something to do with the EM irradiation.
うん 電磁波を 照射してるはずだから
これと 関係があるはずだけど…
Uh... where's the switch...
えーと スイッチは…
You shouldn't do that.
やめた方がいいです
どうして？
Why not?
I don't really know.
分かるんです
なぜか 私 見たことがあるんです
But for some reason I've seen this before.
Perfect fit.
ぴったりだ
Do you project illusions with this or something?
これで 幻を見せられるんですか？
I'm not sure. Sawada didn't know much about how N IV works either.
分からないけど
澤田さんはＮⅣって 装置として 使えるはずだって…
It's doing something.
動きだしましたね
それは？
What's that?
It seems to be the on switch.
起動スイッチだそうです
海翔君？
Kaito...
Kaito! Kaito!
海翔君 海翔君
どうして 発作が
Why... a seizure?
This device...
この装置…
間違いないよ  鹿児島県警って書いてある
There's no mistaking it.
It says Kagoshima Prefectural Police.
つ… つ… 通報しますた
R-R-Reported!
誰が…？
Who did?
They were probably told about
JAXA's situation via mail or Twipo.
メールや 「ツイぽ」で
ＪＡＸＡのことは 伝えておったからな
太陽嵐の混乱のせいで 時間が かかったが
Seems they finally got their act together after that solar flare confusion.
やっと 届いたんじゃろう
タロウちゃん  ボインちゃん
Tarou! Boing!
S-So we might not even need the GunPro-1?
も… もしかして もう ガンつく１とか必要なくね？
You can get a bit of rest here.
ここで 少し休んで
Stop right there.
止まりなさい
Master has instructed me to exterminate you.
あなたたちを排除せよという マスターのご命令です
ゲジ姉…
Sister Centipede...
Your role is so minor in Project Atum that you weren't even named.
君たちは プロジェクトアトゥムにおいて
名前すら 与えられていない 端役にすぎないんだ
Leave the stage already.
速やかに 舞台袖に消えたまえ
なぜ こんなことを するんですか？
Why are you doing this?
Why? Because I want to complete the experiment.
なぜ？ 実験を成功させたいからさ
なぜ 実験を成功させたいんですか？
Why do you want to complete the experiment?
なぜかって？
Why?
実験を成功させたいからだよ
Because I want to complete the experiment.
I thought so.
やっぱり…
You're not the same Mr. Kimijima you used to be.
今の君島さんは 昔とは違う
Back then, Mr. Kimijima thought about nothing but the experiment, but he had a heart.
昔の君島さんは 実験のことしか 考えてなかったけど
思いがあった
He hesitated when he put me to sleep.
私を眠らせるとき 確かに 迷ったんです
He hesitated while talking about his experiment aloud.
口では 実験だと言いながら 迷ってくれたんです
You're different.
今の君島さんは そうじゃない
ただ 目的を果たそうとするだけ
You just want to reach your goal.
Yeah. I guess those are the limitations of a program.
そうだね
それが プログラムの 限界なのかもしれない
だが それ故 目的の遂行は 人間より はるかに 正確に行える
But at the same time, I can proceed with my plans far more precisely than any human could.
Without hesitation.
何の迷いもなく
Sister Centipede.
ゲジ姉
分かりました
Understood.
のっちよー
See you.
They shot each other?
同士打ち…？
Sister Centipede, what is the meaning of this?
ゲジ姉  これは どういうことだ？
不明です
Unknown.
It seems you've got a serious error.
どうやら 君には 深刻なエラーがあるようだね
I'll have to get rid of you.
消えてもらうよ
ゲゲゲ… ジジジ…
Hey, you're the AI Airi, right?
あの… あなたが ＡＩの愛理なんですよね？
I am not Airi. I am Sister Centipede.
愛理ではありません  ゲジ姉です
私が 眠っている間 ずっと 外の世界を 見てきたんですよね？
You kept watching the outside world while I was sleeping, right?
What did you see? Tell me!
何を… 何を見ましたか？
教えてください  私 知りたいんです
I want to know!
Snow...
雪を…
雪を見ました  愛理が…
I saw snow. Airi...
That's amazing!
すごいです 愛理 見たことないです
I've never seen snow!
奇麗でしたか？
Was it pretty?
はい…  とても… とても…
Yes. Very, very.
Very...
とても…
と… ても…
See you, Airi.
のっちよ… 愛理…
Goodbye. See you tomorrow.
さよなら…  また あした…
Goodbye, other me.
さよなら…  もう１人の私…
This much fear could wake you up?
この程度の恐怖で まだ 自我が戻ってくるとは…
What are you so afraid of?
何を おびえている？
Those were unmanned police helicopters.
たかが 無人の偵察ヘリじゃないか
You're planning to kill 5 billion people. Have you forgotten?
君は これから ５０億を殺そうとしているのに
I... I don't...
私は… 私は そんなこと…
With Sister Centipede gone, you're my only card left.
ゲジ姉が消え 駒は 君しか いないんだ
No more accidents are allowed.
もう これ以上のアクシデントは 許されない
人形になってもらうよ
You'll become my puppet.
Good work, everyone!
みんな ホントに お疲れさま
Thanks to your efforts, the upgrade is done!
みんなのおかげで ついに 改良作業が完了しました
Applause!
拍手
Don't even think of saying it doesn't look cool. We don't have the time.
カッコ悪いとか言うのは やめてくださいよ
今は そんなこと…
I won't.
言わないよ
ううん  むしろ すごい カッコイイ
On the contrary, it's really cool.
部長…
President...
How could a robot built by the people of this island be uncool?
島のみんなで 造ったロボットが カッコ悪いわけないじゃん
This isn't the GunPro-1 anymore.
これは もう ガンつく１じゃないよ
Then what is it?
何なんです？
I name it Super GunPro-1!
名付けて…
スーパー ガンつく１
べ… べた過ぎ
That's so l-lame it hurts.
It's not lame! It's awesome!
べたじゃなくて 王道
Akiho!
あき穂ちゃん
Dad!
お父さん
Sorry for making you worry.
心配かけたね
Are you okay? Did you get hurt?
平気？ ケガとかしてない？
I'm fine.
大丈夫だよ
And my sister? Did you meet her?
お姉ちゃんは？ お姉ちゃんに会ったの？
And also, Akiho...
そ… それとね あき穂ちゃん
Yashio... Yashio...
八汐君が…  八汐君が…
Nurse's    office
カイ
Kai!
A doctor looked at him earlier. His life isn't in danger.
さっき 医者に 診てもらったが 命に別条はない
ただ 心臓に 異常な負担が かかった形跡があるから
There are signs that his heart
underwent quite a strain though.
He needs rest.
安静にしてろっていう話だ
His heart?
心臓に？
すみません
I'm sorry.
いえ  私が悪いんです
It was my fault.
ロケットの方は どうなっています？
What's the situation with the rocket?
まだ 特に動きは…
There's no movement.
Then we have a little time to talk, right?
じゃあ 少しは 話せる時間 ありますね
Yes.
はい…
Judging from the attacks against the helicopters, the range of the missiles is 20 km.
ヘリの落下地点から 推測するに
装備されている ミサイルの射程は約２０ｋｍと思われます
The S-S-SUMERAGI is here, so its range...
ス… ス… ＳＵＭＥＲＡＧＩがいるのが ここだから
範囲は…
We can't get anywhere near it then!
これじゃあ 全然 近づけないよ
That's where the program Mr. Sawada gave us comes in.
そこで 澤田氏から 提供された プログラム ＤＧ２９７ですが
By installing the DG297, we can construct a system that Kimijima Kou can't control from the net.
これを インストールすることで
君島コウが ネット上から コントロールできない システムを
構築できることが 分かりました
So you replace Iru-O with that?
つまり 「居ル夫 」を 削除して 入れ替えるってこと？
はい  さらに ＡＲデコイという機能を使って
Yes.
Then, by using its "AR decoy" feature, we might be able to mislead their missiles.
ミサイルを狂わせることも 可能かもしれません
He's also working on a program to erase Kimijima Kou.
あ… あと 君島コウを 消滅させるプログラムも
現在 作ってるらしいお
But either way, safety isn't guaranteed.
ただ どちらにしろ 安全が 保証されるものではなく
使うにしても ガンつく１の 正確な コントロールが 必要になります
We'll need perfect control of the GunPro-1.
八汐君 できるのかな？
Can Yashio do it?
The doctor said he needs rest...
安静って言われてたが？
別のオペレーターを 考えるべきでしょう
We need to find another operator.
President, I hope you don't mind.
部長 いいですね？
I knew you were talking about that.
やっぱり…
そういう話になってんじゃ ないかって思ってたんだよね
Kai!
カイ
I'll do it.
乗るよ
But!
でも…
Doesn't it set you on fir—
そういうのも たぎるんじゃない？
カイ
Kai!
I must say it's impossible for you now.
その状態では 無理と言わざるを得ません
Sadly, this time it's not just a gam—
残念ですが 今回は 遊びとは…
I know!
そんなの 分かってるよ
Yashio...
先輩…
The GunPro-1 needs to dodge SUMERAGI's attack and launch the pile bunker.
ＳＵＭＥＲＡＧＩの あの攻撃を ガンつく１で かわして
パイルバンカー 撃ち込むんだ
That's more than just simply hopeless.
無理ゲーどころの話じゃない
Normally even I couldn't do it.
普通にいったら 俺でも 無理だよ
What are you getting at?
な… 何？ その口ぶり
も… も… もしかして？
Wait, do you...
うん  あるだろう  俺だけが使える チート技が
Yeah.
There's a cheat only I can use.
What do you mean?
どういうことです？
俺さ 発作を持ってるんだよね
I've got my seizures, you see.
A single second lasts twelve times longer for me.
１秒間を 何倍にも感じる発作
I call it slow-motion.
スローモーっていうんだけど
カイ…？
Kai...
That device can trigger a seizure artificially.
この装置は その発作を 意図的に 引き起こせるんだ
With that I could follow SUMERAGI's movements.
これを使えば ＳＵＭＥＲＡＧＩの動きを 読み切ることができる
So? Only I—
どう？ 俺じゃなきゃ…
No!
駄目だよ
The doctor told you that it's a huge strain on your heart!
お医者さんに言われたんでしょ？
心臓に 異常な負担が かかってるって
それは 発作のときは いつもでしょ？
That's what happens during my seizures.
違う
It's different.
普段の発作の後よりも 明らかに つらそうだもん
It looks a lot worse than your usual seizures.
きっと その装置 すごい強力なんだよ
That device must be really powerful.
I guess.
かもね  でも 何とか…
But what—
You might even die!
死ぬかもしれないんだよ！？
それで 戦って…
What's the point in fighting if you die?
カイが 死んじゃったら どうするの
Akiho!
あき穂ちゃん！
I've got a message.
今 連絡があって
ロケットが ＶＡＢを出て 射点に向かったそうです
The rocket left the VAB for the launch pad.
X-7 to 8 hours.
Ｘ マイナス ７から８時間です！
I knew you'd be here.
ここしか ないよね
When Misa left the island, she told me to take care of you.
俺さ ミサ姉が 島 出るとき
アキちゃんのこと頼むって 言われたんだ
I know.
知ってる
I see...
そっか…
でも 俺 ゲームばっかり やってたでしょ？
But all I did was play my game...
No.
嘘…
I know.
うち 知ってるよ
Mizuka once told me that the passion fruit buns sell because of me.
瑞榎姉に １回 言われたことある
「お前のおかげで パッションフルーツまんが売れる」って
That you're making efforts for my sake.
カイ いつも うちのために 頑張ってくれてたって
You acted cool, distanced yourself, and intentionally didn't come to the club,
冷たいこと言って 突き放して
わざと ロボ部 サボったりしても
but you were always with me when I needed you the most.
大事なときは いつも 一緒にいてくれた
You wouldn't quit the Robotics Club.
絶対 ロボ部は 辞めなかった
You've done enough for me already.
カイは もう じゅうぶん
うちのために 頑張ってくれたんだよ
だから もう…
You shouldn't—
That won't do.
駄目なんだよ それじゃあ
俺はさ アキちゃんとミサ姉を
I must let you and Misa face each other properly.
ちゃんと 会わせなきゃいけないんだよ
俺は そのために 頑張ってきたんだ
That's what I worked for.
だから…
So when I'm in trouble, push this without hesitation.
俺が ピンチになったら ためらわず これを押して
I want to take you to Misa.
アキちゃんを ミサ姉の所に 連れていきたいんだ
Kai...
カイ…
お願い
Please.
Aki!
アキちゃん
Promise me you won't die.
約束して…  死なないって
I promise.
約束する
You've gotta keep it!
絶対だよ！ 絶対だからね
There's no way out for you!
Yeah. I won't die.
ああ  絶対 死なない
You promised!
絶対だからね…
Hey, Kai...
ねえ カイ…
There's something I want to tell you after this is over.
あのね 戦いが終わったら 聞いてほしいことがあるんだ
What?
何？
Well...
それは…
Wait, would this set the death flag?
でも これって 死亡フラグになっちゃうか
俺さ…
You know, I love you.
アキちゃんのこと 好きだ
聞こえなかった？
You couldn't hear?
I... I could...
き… き… 聞こえたけど…
そんな あっさり…
So suddenly...
I don't really have anything else...
でも 他に言いようないし…
But how should I...
で… でも 何ていうか…
Uh, well...
その…  あの…
Aki.
アキちゃん
Yeah?
はい
Think I could hear your response?
返事とか… 聞かせてくれる？
But are you really fine with me?
っていうか ホ… ホントに うちで いいのかっていうか…
何で？
Why?
な… 何でって…
Well...
ほ… ほら フラウ坊とか 綯さんとか お姉ちゃんだって…
There's Frau Bow and Ms. Nae and even my sister...
What've they got to do with this?
何で そんな名前が出てくるの？
何でって…
What what?
もう
Geez!
That was too sudden, Kai!
いきなり過ぎるよ カイは
そう？
Really?
I thought I managed to go on not saying it for quite a while...
これでも じゅうぶん 言わずに 我慢してきたつもりだけど
じゃあさ あめちゃん ある？
Anyway. Got any candy?
And...
それと…
Can I get a kiss as a blessing from the Goddess of Victory?
勝利の女神の祝福ってことで
キスしていい？
I can't?
駄目？
Okay, this time.
じゃあ 特別…
Tastes like melon soda.
メロンソーダの味…
I was drinking Fruit Sour Melon.
フルーツサワーメロン飲んだから
Take care of my sister.
お姉ちゃんのこと よろしくね
Die, normalfags!
はぜろ リア充！！
な… 何か 見てて 恥ずかしくなっちゃった  ねっ？
Wasn't just looking at them embarrassing?
Hidaka, do you have a thing for Akiho?
日高君 まさか あき穂ちゃんのこと…
W-Whyat are you shaying?!
にゃ… にゃにを言ってるんですか
Requesting the twist revealing your secret feelings for Yashio, kthx!
む… む… むしろ 八汐先輩に
ひそかに 思いを寄せていた展開 キボンヌ
What're you saying?!
何 言ってる
むしろ 八汐先輩を 好きだったのは 古郡だろう
You loved him, didn't you, Furugoori?!
ぬなっ
よーし こうなったら 円陣だ！
Now that it's come to this, team meeting!
じゃあ いくよ
It's time to make a move!
絶対 成功させようね
We must succeed!
With the power of dreams and friendship!
夢と友情パワーで
All together!
みんな 一緒に
Tane High Robotics!
チュウタネロボ部
Genki Punch!
元気一発
よいらーいき！！
All together!
Somebody said that this is a fight the fate of the world hinges upon.
世界を救う戦いだと 誰かが言った
Somebody said that the fate of
mankind rests on our shoulders.
お前たちに 全人類の希望が 懸かっていると 誰かが言った
Countdown!
カウント スリー ツー ワン リフトオフ
3! 2! 1!
Liftoff!
But I really don't care about things like that.
でも 俺にとって そんなことは 興味なくて…
Laser gun support, um... loaded onto the Thunder Emperor.
レーザー光銃座  サンダーエンペラーに えっと…
積み込み済みだよ～
システムリンク オンライン
System link online.
Switch your PokeCom to a wired connection.
ポケコンを有線に  赤いケーブルね
It's the red cable.
周辺マップ ロード開始
Begin loading the area map.
3 meters! 5! 7!
３ｍ ５ ７ １０
No problems with the laser scanner on either side.
レーザースキャナー左右共に異常 なし
10! 15! 20!
１５！ ２０！ 範囲最大
Maximum range.
T-T-Terrain analyzer AI functional.
ち… ち… 地形判断用ＡＩ 正常
Checks done.
チェックは 以上
Kai, it's time for the main show! Are you ready?
カイ  ぶっつけ本番だけど いける？
最初から 分かってたことでしょ？
We've planned this from the start.
いまさら ノーゴーだなんて 言わないでよ
How could we back out now?
カイ…
Kai...
コンディション オールグリーン
All conditions are green.
最終判断は ゴー
The final decision is...
Go!
ガンヴァレル 発進
Gunvarrel!
Launch!
それはふとした瞬間に
All those unexpected moments
As you mumble on and on
君がつぶやくいくつもの言葉
Will overcome even my standards
それがいつしか価値観さえも
超えてしまうんだよ
In the end
All those goodbyes we said
いくつもの別れを告げ 僕らは
As we climb the stairway to the future
明日への階段をのぼる
とめどなく零れ落ちる雫も
Just as raindrops fall no matter what we do
光が照らすなら この星は繋がっている
Light will always hold this planet together
奇跡のように命が集まって
Lives gather as if by some miracle
Showing the outline of a lively scene
にぎやかな景色は輪郭になる
An epilogue so bright it brings tears to our eyes
泣きたい眩しいエピローグ
取り上げる思いが
The sky painted by the hearts of those looking up
描いた空
柔らかな風が吹き
The wind blows gently stroking
Turning into a new path
新しい道となり
A path that will always
いつだってその道は
Lead us to this place
この場所に繋がってる
Tune in next week too!